<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:id="c5653" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Peiping, China</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt/>
            <notesStmt>
                <relatedItem target="c5652" type="prev"/>
                <relatedItem target="c5654" type="next"/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc/>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <facsimile>
        <surfaceGrp>
            <surface xml:id="c5653f1">
                <graphic height="3018px" url="07374.tif" width="4814px"/>
                <fs type="vendor-index">
                    <f name="label">
                        <string>Peiping, China</string>
                    </f>
                    <f name="order">
                        <numeric value="2.1"/>
                    </f>
                    <f name="color">
                        <symbol value="w"/>
                    </f>
                    <f name="status">
                        <symbol value="d"/>
                    </f>
                    <f name="year">
                        <string>1949</string>
                    </f>
                    <f name="scan-sequence">
                        <string>07374</string>
                    </f>
                </fs>
            </surface>
            <surface xml:id="c5653f2">
                <graphic height="3018px" url="07375.tif" width="4814px"/>
                <fs type="vendor-index">
                    <f name="label">
                        <string>Peiping, China</string>
                    </f>
                    <f name="order">
                        <numeric value="2.2"/>
                    </f>
                    <f name="color">
                        <symbol value="w"/>
                    </f>
                    <f name="status">
                        <symbol value="d"/>
                    </f>
                    <f name="year">
                        <string>1950</string>
                    </f>
                    <f name="scan-sequence">
                        <string>07375</string>
                    </f>
                </fs>
            </surface>
        </surfaceGrp>
    </facsimile>
    <text corresp="#c5653">
        <body>
            <div corresp="#c5653f1">
                <head>Peiping #2</head>
                <p>7/23/49 Tgm 538 from Tientsin re closing USIS offices (request of Local Military
                    - see Tientsin card) Waddell-FE states also closed at Nanking, Shanghai, Peiping
                    &amp; Hankow.</p>
                <p>1/24/50 - DA Mailing Notice No. 11 <unclear/> Tientsin instructed on January 14,
                    1950 to close as soon as transportation could be arranged. Brit. to handle
                    American interests. Mail should be sent in accordance with Dept. Regs., Dept.
                    Announcement No. 221 and DA Mailing Notice No. 1.</p>
                <p>2/7/50 - Tel. 302 2/7/50 from Peiping: Following official seals destroyed Jan.
                    11: 1 metal impression, 2 rubber stamps, 1 metal wax impression AMCONGEN
                    Changchun; 2 rubber stamps AMCON Changchun; 1 metal impression, 1 rubber stamp,
                    (CONT 374 F) 1 metal wax impression AMCONGEN Harbin, all foregoing seals having
                    been entrusted custody ConGen on closure Changchun office Feb. 21,1948. Also
                    destroyed metal impression seal 1 rubber stamp, 1 metal wax impression inscribed
                    AMCON Peiping, these latter being in disuse.</p>
                <p>2/15/50 - Navy Dept. tel to Dept. of this date No. 152031Z re auth. to Peiping to
                    destroy ASTALUSNA files.</p>
                <p>2/21/50 - Deptel. 157 to Peiping relating message from Chief of Naval Operations
                    to destroy ASTALUSNA files,</p>
            </div>
            <div corresp="#c5653f2">
                <head>Peiping</head>
                <table>
                    <row role="label">
                        <cell>3/1/50</cell>
                        <cell>Shanghai tel. 905 3/1/50 listing classified material addressed
                            Peiping/Tientsin/Mukden destroyed.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>2/25/50</cell>
                        <cell>Peiping Tel. 404, 2/25/50 - Consulate proposes turn over protection
                            services Brit. Consulate Gen. about mid-March in order that there shall
                            be short trial period while we are still in Peiping for
                            consultation.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>3/6/50</cell>
                        <cell>Tel. 460, 3/6/50 from Peiping re restoration of Con. telephone service
                            as of 3/4/50.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>3/3/50</cell>
                        <cell>Tel. 451, March 3, 1950 from Peiping - Peiping USIS files in main
                            destroyed.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>3/10/50</cell>
                        <cell>Tel. 494 from Peiping of March 10 - 3 cases refrigerator parts and
                            publications shipped Hong Kong per SS Hunan departing Taku Bar March
                            2</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>3/9/50</cell>
                        <cell>Tel. 486, 3/9/50, listing date of departure of personnel. also Tel.
                            458, 3/6/50 from Peiping.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>3/16/50</cell>
                        <cell>DEPTEL to Peiping 234, 3/16/50 - Submit list destroyed files.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>3/17/50</cell>
                        <cell>Peiping tel. 525, March 15 approved. DEPTEL 238, March 17 to Peiping -
                            Dept. concurred opinion Nanking regarding issue renewal passports when
                            passports expire after July 1 for two reasons - 1. Grant passport
                            facilities carries implication this govt. can and will protect holder.
                            2. limitation outstanding valid passports lessens danger passports being
                            used to detriment US if lost stolen. Dept offers no objection renewal or
                            issue passports when present passports will expire any time up to end
                            1950 if holders reside interior</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
