<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:id="c5675" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Shanghai, China</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt/>
            <notesStmt>
                <relatedItem target="c5674" type="prev"/>
                <relatedItem target="c5676" type="next"/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc/>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <facsimile>
        <surfaceGrp>
            <surface xml:id="c5675f1">
                <graphic height="3022px" url="07409.tif" width="4802px"/>
                <fs type="vendor-index">
                    <f name="label">
                        <string>Shanghai, China</string>
                    </f>
                    <f name="order">
                        <numeric value="3.1"/>
                    </f>
                    <f name="color">
                        <symbol value="w"/>
                    </f>
                    <f name="status">
                        <symbol value="d"/>
                    </f>
                    <f name="year">
                        <string>1950</string>
                    </f>
                    <f name="scan-sequence">
                        <string>07409</string>
                    </f>
                </fs>
            </surface>
            <surface xml:id="c5675f2">
                <graphic height="3022px" url="07410.tif" width="4802px"/>
                <fs type="vendor-index">
                    <f name="label">
                        <string>Shanghai, China</string>
                    </f>
                    <f name="order">
                        <numeric value="3.2"/>
                    </f>
                    <f name="color">
                        <symbol value="w"/>
                    </f>
                    <f name="status">
                        <symbol value="d"/>
                    </f>
                    <f name="year">
                        <string>1950</string>
                    </f>
                    <f name="scan-sequence">
                        <string>07410</string>
                    </f>
                </fs>
            </surface>
        </surfaceGrp>
    </facsimile>
    <text corresp="#c5675">
        <body>
            <div corresp="#c5675f1">
                <head>SHANGHAI - pg. 3</head>
                <p>3/1/50 - Shanghai tel 905 3/1/50 listing classified material addressed
                    Peiping/Tientsin/Mukden destroyed.</p>
                <p>3/9/50 - Shanghai Tel 1030 Mar 9 states Press monitoring Shanghai will cease as
                    of 3/11/50/</p>
                <p>3/9/50 - Deptel 387 3/9/50 to Manila - Ship Shanghai files not needed Manila to
                    Dept via/vessel, custody Commanding Officer and US Despatch Agent, San
                    Francisco.</p>
                <p>3/13/50 - Shanghai Tel. 1076, 3/13/50 - CONGEN will ship dossiers of applicants
                    for US visas who are unable leave Shanghai to Tokyo which will serve as
                    distribution center. From there dossiers can be transferred to any point where
                    applicant may be able to proceed at later date or returned to Shanghai if and
                    when this CONGEN reopened.</p>
                <p>3/4/50 - Tel. 949 of March 4 from Shanghai - Quota registration records packed
                    and will be sent Tokyo accordance DEPTINSTRS if can pass Chinese customs.</p>
                <p>3/10/50 - Tel. 1044, March 10, from Shanghai - CONGEN has destroyed CRM
                    classified files items one to fifteen contained in Box 9, addressed to National
                    Archives, Wash., D.C. from mission China, balance of which will be stored with
                    British CONGEN for onward shipment when feasible. Files destroyed include
                    incoming outgoing, telegrams to and from AMEMBASSY, Nanking, CONGEN Shanghai,
                    Department from restricted to secret, confidential memos of negotiations with
                    China, and confidential memos, despatches and correspondence, disclosure of
                    which would be prejudicial <unclear>way</unclear> interests USA.</p>
            </div>
            <div corresp="#c5675f2">
                <head>Con't 'd</head>
                <p>3/10/50 - Disposal witnessed by Fleming as security officer and Hinke Commercial
                    Attache. All telegrams despatches and presumably bulk of memos and letters to
                    Chinese officials on file Wash.</p>
                <p>3/14/50 - Tel. from Shanghai TOECA 57 of 3/14/50 re ECA making every effort
                    evacuate essential files and SRO operations reports but Commies attitude obscure
                    and success dependent upon last minute development. If unable evacuate files
                    reports, will entrust to British.</p>
                <p>3/15/50 - Tel #1095, 3/15/50 from Shanghai for Killion American President Lines
                    San Francisco from Downs Shanghai - CONGEN facilities no longer available for
                    reply.</p>
                <p>TEX</p>
                <p>3/16/50 - Shanghai tel. 1118, March 16, Active files being shipped Tokyo if
                    Chinese customs permits export: Dossiers applicants pending: 15-drawer cabinet
                    inventory number A5.129 and 4 four-drawer cabinets inventory numbers A5.126,
                    A5.127, A5.132, A5.139. Alphabetical quota registration file 14-drawer 3 x 5
                    card file inventory number A5.180. One regulation quota registration book.
                    Unclassified visa files containing records visas issued and mandatory or
                    prejudicial refusals will remain custody British Shanghai.</p>
                <p>√3/17/50 - Deptel 460, 3/17/50 to Manila authorizing shipment of biographical and
                    political files. to Dept.</p>
                <p>3/21/50 - Shanghai tel of this date re transmitter and receiver seized.</p>
                <p>3/18/50 - Shanghai tel 1141, 3/18/50 - Close of business March 15, 1950. British
                    to handle US interests. DA Mailing Notice of 3/22/50 #46.</p>
                <p>4/27/50- DA mailing Notice #69- Closed officially 4/25/50. Shanghai unnumbered
                    tel. 4/26/- official closing 4/28/50.</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
