<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:id="c5686" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Tsingtao, China</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt/>
            <notesStmt>
                <relatedItem target="c5685" type="prev"/>
                <relatedItem target="c5687" type="next"/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc/>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <facsimile>
        <surfaceGrp>
            <surface xml:id="c5686f1">
                <graphic height="3016px" url="07428.tif" width="4806px"/>
                <fs type="vendor-index">
                    <f name="label">
                        <string>Tsingtao, China</string>
                    </f>
                    <f name="order">
                        <numeric value="2.1"/>
                    </f>
                    <f name="color">
                        <symbol value="w"/>
                    </f>
                    <f name="status">
                        <symbol value="d"/>
                    </f>
                    <f name="year">
                        <string>1950</string>
                    </f>
                    <f name="scan-sequence">
                        <string>07428</string>
                    </f>
                </fs>
            </surface>
            <surface xml:id="c5686f2">
                <graphic height="3016px" url="07429.tif" width="4806px"/>
                <fs type="vendor-index">
                    <f name="label">
                        <string>Tsingtao, China</string>
                    </f>
                    <f name="order">
                        <numeric value="2.2"/>
                    </f>
                    <f name="color">
                        <symbol value="w"/>
                    </f>
                    <f name="status">
                        <symbol value="d"/>
                    </f>
                    <f name="year">
                        <string/>
                    </f>
                    <f name="scan-sequence">
                        <string>07429</string>
                    </f>
                </fs>
            </surface>
        </surfaceGrp>
    </facsimile>
    <text corresp="#c5686">
        <body>
            <div corresp="#c5686f1">
                <head>Tsingtao</head>
                <p>Despatch No. 16 of this date from Tsingtao re Commie refusal to recognize Brit.
                    custody of American Gov. owned property in Tsingtao, either moveable or
                    immoveable. Former Navy barracks at 1 Kwangsi Rd. and Dept. fuel stocks stored
                    on the premises confiscated by Commies. All U.S. Govt. immoveable propt. not
                    previously confiscated, i.e., the buildings at 2 and 3 Lanshan Rd., 1 First
                    Taiping Chuoh Rd. and 9 Shanhakua Rd., together with all Govt. moveable prop.
                    situated therein, was duly taken over on Nov. 22, 1949. Consular commissary
                    valued at some $4,100.00 turned over to Brit. ConGen. Twelve motor vehicles and
                    certain other equipment sold through a Soviet firm for $6,600.00. Two motor
                    vehicles left at CONGEN taken over by Commies. Property of Tsingtao Amer. School
                    turned over to Mr. Stockwell B. Sears, representing School Board. Property of
                    former Amer. Armed Services YMCA left to Chinese YMCA. Receipt obtained from new
                    occupants of privately owned house formerly occupied by Carl O. Hawthorne at 2
                    Branch Cheng Yang Kuan Rd. covering few articles of US Govt. prop. there.</p>
                <p>Letter to Mr. Freeman from Carl Hawthorne (Tsingtao)- Commies got no
                    cryptographic material or other classified matter when they moved in on us on
                    Nov. 21. All archives were sent to Wash. prior to the Commie occupation and
                    thereafter, except for routine unclassified correspondence. No file copies
                    retained. No opportunity to destroy radio equipment (which had been reduced to
                    minimum of one transmitter and one receiver).</p>
            </div>
            <div corresp="#c5686f2">
                <head>This fell into Commie hands, but on auth. of Paul Yao, one of former radio
                    operators, Commies burnt up set during first week of attempted use since they
                    did not know how to operate it.</head>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
